JEBA ROBERT

(+91) 9867100812

jebasalomi199835@gmail.com

Mumbai



linkedin.com/in/jeba-robert/github.com/jebarobert

jebarobert.github.io/my-portfolio



SUMMARY

Dedicated **DevOps engineer** with 5 years of professional expertise, with a focus on DevOps using cloud platforms, DevOps tools, and Front-End tools.

Strongly driven and outcome-oriented leader who coaches teams of more than thirty employees on DevOps technologies. a devoted team player who is great at collaborating with others and who is focused on optimizing a facility's production process



SKILLS

- DevOps/Automation: Ansible, AWX, Jenkins, Terraform, Gitlab, ServiceNow (workflows; forms; orchestration; NLU), Jfrog Artifactory, Hashicorp Vault, Docker, Kubernetes
- Cloud: AWS EC2, VPC, S3, IAM, Azure
- Scripting Languages: PowerShell, Python Scripting, Bash
- Front End: Angular JS, React JS
- Soft Skills: Research, Leadership, Mentorship, analytics, Presentation skills, Problem Solving
- Others: Rest API, DBMS, SQL, JavaScript



EXPERIENCE

AUG 2022 - Present

Consultant | Capgemini | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Implemented 25+ high-impact automations in Ansible, Gitlab, Terraform, Jenkins, Docker and Kubernetes, delivered substantial efficiency improvements, resulting in the elimination of 500 Full Time Equivalent (FTE) hours monthly, boosting productivity and cost savings.
- Mentored a team of 15 members on Terraform and Provided Windows Automation for the first time in client environment
- Implemented HashiCorp vault for secure credentials storage and Jfrog Artifactory for artifacts, binaries and files
- Provided SIP by developing generic roles and documented the Automation with complete package
 of user manual, test results, flows and procedure
- worked together with stakeholders to fully comprehend the aims and objectives of the project
- Developed successful solutions for clients by utilizing FSD papers and a tried-and-true procedure
- Configured, managed, and monitored cloud-based services such as AWS EC2, S3, VPC, IAM and RDS using Terraform and Ansible
- Designed dashboards for visualizing the automations using Angular JS and React JS
- Developed protocols to automate code deployments and builds in accordance with standards and guidelines, and effectively executed up to 70% of the automations
- Implemented systems automation using scripting languages like PowerShell and Python

JAN 2020 - AUG 2022

Engineer - Cloud & Infra Services | LTI | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Identified and automated areas/categories saving minimum of 400 person hours.
- Worked closely with the operation teams to understand the requirement and creating new automation for service request to reduce the number of incidents.
- Worked with internal team, gathered requirements of client and did R&D for New IT Infrastructure automations which can help to automate the service request.
- Orchestrated ServiceNow using Ansible and Jenkins.
- Designed server provisioning and features deployment using Ansible and Terraform.
- Automated and deployed scripts in PowerShell to generate Reports on Weekly/Monthly Basis.

EDUCATION

June 2019 - May 2021

Master of Science in Information Technology | SIES

- Percentage: 93.4% (CGPA: 9.83) (Rank 1)
- Research Paper: Mobile games: Expectations and Interests of the users
- Projects: Fake Product Identification System (Android Studio, Java, MySql, Blockchain), Embellish English (React JS, Bootstrap)

June 2016 - May 2019

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology | SIES

- Percentage: 82.65% (CGPA:8.7)
- Project: Online Sweets Shop (Madhuram) (ASP.NET, C#, MySQL, Bootstrap)

Y AWARDS

- **Delivery Excellence** Award (Capgemini) (2023)
- Won **Best Manager**'s Award from LTI CIS Academy (2021)
- Endowment Award First Rank in M.Sc. IT (2021)
- Geeta Israani Scholarship Award in TY (2019)

© CERTIFICATIONS

- LTI Certified Cloud & Infrastructure Services Professional
- Fundamentals of Database System (NPtel Online Certification) Percentage: 70%
- Demystifying Networking (NPtel Online Certification) Percentage: 78%
- Advanced Relational Database and SQL(Coursera) Grade Achieved: 90%
- Getting Started with Google Apps Script (Coursera) Grade Achieved: 100%
- Introduction to Python Scripting for DevOps (Coursera) Grade Achieved: 90%
- Business Analytics for Decision-Making (Coursera) Grade Achieved: 93.65%
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified: Microsoft Azure Administrator Associate
- Getting Started with Azure DevOps Boards (Coursera)
- Containerization I/O Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift (Coursera)